<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Julian Stanley</title>
    <link>https://julianstanley.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Julian Stanley</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://julianstanley.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peer Review: SensorOverlord Paper</title>
      <link>https://julianstanley.com/blog/sensoroverlord_reviews/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstanley.com/blog/sensoroverlord_reviews/</guid>
      <description>Overview and purpose I would like to keep a record of my submission history and peer review results for each of my first-author papers and grants.
I&amp;rsquo;ve heard that the peer review process can be really disheartening for many people, and that it often involves many, many rounds of rejection.
I also appreciate reading peer reviews, and think that they can be helpful to read after reading a published paper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SSD Formatting and Install in Ubuntu 19.04</title>
      <link>https://julianstanley.com/blog/ubuntu_ssd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstanley.com/blog/ubuntu_ssd/</guid>
      <description>Today I upgraded the base 256 GB SSD (2.5 mm) on my Thinkpad T460 to a 1 TB Samsung 860 EVO.
It took me a few google searches to learn how to make the transition. In the end, I used Tuxboot to make a bootable Clonezilla USB drive, and then GParted to resize my partition. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I did step-by-step:
Connect your new SSD via USB. I used a StarTech cable from Amazon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connecting a remote MongoDB database with R/Shiny</title>
      <link>https://julianstanley.com/blog/mongo_rshiny/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://julianstanley.com/blog/mongo_rshiny/</guid>
      <description>While making a Shiny App for a lab project (Sensor Overlord), I wanted to create a feature where users could input sensor data into a database, where it could be accessible to other users.
I decided to give MongoDB a shot, mostly becuase of the free hosting services available on MongoDB&amp;rsquo;s website.
And it was actually extremely straightforward. There are great resources available online, like the mongolite user manual and the shiny persistent data storage page.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
